<speak>
    Disciple Tools and Make.com Integration. First Scenario Workflow.

    The aim of this guide is to walk you through the initial steps of setting up and executing your very first Disciple Tools, Make.com custom application scenario workflow.

    <break time="500ms"/>
    <emphasis level="strong">Step 1. Make.com Registration.</emphasis>

    Make your way over to Make.com and if you have not already done so, register a new account.

    <break time="500ms"/>
    <emphasis level="strong">Step 2. Initial Login.</emphasis>

    Once you have completed the registration process and login to Make.com for the first time, you will be presented with a My Organization dashboard.

    Before proceeding any further, it is recommended you spend some time reviewing Make's Documentation, to familiarise yourself with it's common features.

    The scenarios section is a prerequisite to better understand the following steps.

    <break time="500ms"/>
    <emphasis level="strong">Step 3. Create a D.T. Site Link.</emphasis>

    A site-link token shall be required, in order to successfully establish a connection between Disciple Tools and Make.com.

    View D.T. Site Links Documentation for detailed instructions on how to create site-links and source required transfer tokens.

    Ensure Token As Transfer Key is selected; whilst also making a note of generated Token; which will be required later.

    <break time="500ms"/>
    <emphasis level="strong">Step 4. First Make Scenario - Configuration.</emphasis>

    Return back to the Make Dashboard and navigate to the scenarios section.

    Select the Create a new scenario option in the top-right corner, to enter into scenario editor mode.

    We shall create a very simple scenario workflow; which ingest Google Spreadsheet entries and using the information, creates a new DT record using the Disciple Tools Create Post Type Record module.

    In the top-left corner, name your scenario. For example: Disciple Tools - Demo.

    Ensure to save changes as you go!

    Next, click the button in the center of the screen, to add our first app; which, in our case, will be Google Sheets.

    Wow! So many modules to choose from!

    Then, select the actual module we wish to deploy within our scenario. In our case, we are interested in modules of type Trigger; for example: Watch Rows.

    You will then be prompted to establish a connection to the account storing target Google Sheet to be processed.

    Click add, to create a new connection.

    Google's Client ID and Client Secret can be found within their Developer Console and are optional.

    The actual steps taken to generate credentials, are beyond the scope of this document, but further information can be found in Authenticate using API keys.

    Aternatively, if no client id or secret is specified, you will be automatically prompted to grant access to your target Google account.

    Once Google connection has been established, select spreadsheet to be processed.

    Once all settings have been specified, click ok and save scenario.

    Now is a good time as any, to test the configured module.

    Right-click on the module and select the Run this module only option.

    As our spreadsheet does not contain any values, we are not expecting to see any module outputs; but, we are expecting a successful run!

    Now, let's see some data!

    Navigate to the target Google Spreadsheet and enter some values.

    Notice the use of actual D.T. field value keys within Age, Language & Milestones columns; which is required when submitting record creation request.

    Typically, the Google Spreadsheet will be an intermediary staging area; used to store information captured from a web form; which would present field value labels; whilst storing actual value keys or ids.

    Re-run the module and view generated output; which should present spreadsheet row entries.

    Now, let's add D.T's creation module!

    Click on the Watch Rows side tab to add a new module.

    Search for the Disciple Tools application.

    Search for the Create Post Type Record module and add.

    Similar to the Google connection, create a new D.T connection to the target D.T instance.

    Whilst creating the connection, you will be prompted to enter values for the following fields.

    DT Base URL.

    This is the URL (including https:// protocol) to your D.T instance.

    Please ensure to omit the terminating forward slash at the end of the URL, as this is automatically assigned.

    API Key.

    This is the D.T site link token; which was generated in step 3.

    Post Type.

    This is the target post type key; which will be used shortly, whilst mapping fields.

    Once connection fields have been populated, click save to be presented with a list of specified post type fields.

    At this junction, you will now map the presented D.T post type fields against the incoming fields from the connected module; Google Sheets, Watch Rows, in our case.

    On completion, you should have the following mappings.

    Click ok and save latest scenario updates.

    Now, let's put our scenario workflow to the test!

    <break time="500ms"/>
    <emphasis level="strong">Step 5. First Make Scenario - Workflow Run.</emphasis>

    In order to test our workflow, simply click the Run once option in the bottom-left corner of the editor view.

    In the event of the workflow failing to run end-to-end, ensure to save scenario, navigate to the main dashboard and re-enter scenario; to ensure all changes have taken effect!

    Another gotcha to be aware of, is knowing the conditions your connected modules (Google Sheets - Watch Rows in our case), will trigger. As the workflow would stop if there is no data to be processed.

    Therefore, in our case, a new speadsheet row signals fresh data to be processed.

    On a successful run, all modules should be in a green state.

    In the event of errors, inspect the browser console for more detailed information.

    View module outputs to sanity check processed data.

    <break time="500ms"/>
    <emphasis level="strong">Step 6. D.T. Created Record Sanity Check.</emphasis>

    As a final sanity check, navigate to your D.T. instance and confirm submitted record has indeed been created.

    Congratulations, as you now have a functioning Make.com scenario workflow!

    From this point forward, you are now free to explore integrating the D.T. Create module with other apps more suitable to your use case.

    <break time="500ms"/>
    <emphasis level="strong">Happy Making!</emphasis>
</speak>